nowadays I'm making anywhere from 5050
to 100 to even $120,000 in one single
day and this is all done with pretty
much about an hour or two a day that's
it doesn't really require any much more
time and obviously I'm only working
Monday through Friday and one of the
most common questions that I get asked
from my whole entire Community is how
would I start again from scratch and in
this video I'm going to tell you exactly
what I would do if I would have to start
from zero learning how to date TR okay
so step one learn the candlesticks we
are trading Candlestick patterns so we
simply have to learn how to read the
candlesticks I was so against that
because I just wanted to learn how I to
click by how I click sell and how I
withdraw the money into my bank account
but before even doing that you have to
learn how to speak the language it's
almost like wanting to learn Spanish and
wanting to pick up a Latina in Colombia
like yeah obviously you want to pick up
the girl on the street but in order for
you to do that you have to learn the
language first and then learn your ways
around it so you can go up and talk to
her I just wanted to pick up the girl
and take her home that's not how this
this works in the market you can't just
go to the market click buy or sell and
then take the money no first you have to
learn what is a Candlestick so the first
point is read the Candlestick Bible is
going to teach you every single
Candlestick formation going to teach you
every single Candlestick rejection every
single Candlestick confirmation and it's
going to teach you the language of the
candlesticks that you're going to be
looking at every single day a lot of
people say that the candlesticks look
like Chinese for whatever reason but
it's actually very easy to comprehend so
the first step is learn the candlesticks
that you're going going to be eventually
clicking buy and sell where you're going
to make the money from so step two is
going to be learning the platform that
you're going to actually be analyzing
and executing these trades so after you
already read the candlesticks and you
know what you're looking for and you're
ready to click buy or sell you need to
learn these two platforms and these two
platforms only at the beginning I was so
scared and confused because there's so
many scam websites out there that are
ready to take your money or are not
trustworthy and it makes it a very scary
Journey at the beginning because you
don't know where to go or who to ask and
I'm here to tell you you only need these
two platforms and that is it the first
one is going to be tradingview.com this
is where you're going to analyze your
markets this is where you're going to
see what pair you want to buy sell Etc
trading view is where you're going to
analyze your markets every single day
and this is where you're going to be
reading the Candlestick patterns the
second platform is going to be metat
Trader 4 or metat Trader 5 this is where
the execution takes place so you connect
a broker a broker of your choice and
then you connect it to the execution
platform which is metatrader 4 or metat
Trad 5 here's where you actually click
buy or sell in real time so once you go
to trading view you find the pair that
you want to take the trade on then you
go to metat Trader 4 and then you
execute the trade and that's it you
don't need any other platform any other
platform it may be a newsletter platform
or a position size calculator but
realistically you don't need any of
those these are the only two platforms
you need step three is learning a
strategy guys you you simply cannot make
money in the market without having a
proven strategy that is the Simplicity
of it if you want to make 50 to 100K how
I do every single day in trading you
need to have a foolproof strategy you
can't just come into the market and
expect a month of you clicking a couple
buttons that you're going to make a
profitable equation that's just not how
this works like it it just doesn't make
any sense if not everybody in the world
would be rich so you need to find a
mentor or find a strategy that has a
proven track record that it works save
yourself the time of trying to make your
own I did it and honestly I really
regret doing it because it was just a
money pit I was just throwing money into
it and it was going down in flames it
literally made no sense and this journey
of you learning a strategy has to be
done on your own don't try and do it
with a friend don't try and do it with a
brother with a sister it won't work you
guys are going to see the market in very
different ways it's almost like learning
a language you guys can learn a language
at the same time but you might have a
different accent than the other person
you might say things differently in a
different organization it's the same
thing when it comes to trading you can
read the market one way and then your
partner your friend whoever can read it
a different way so you have to go into
this alone and it's a very dark and
lonely Journey but I can guarantee you
there is light at the end of the tunnel
and that is something that I would
definitely do if I were to have to start
over because I tried to get into this
with three of my close friends from high
school and they were simply a drag they
would literally hold me back because
they simply weren't as passionate about
it as I was every single morning I'd
wake up and I'd be ready to learn
trading and I'd be ready to see what the
market has to offer versus them they
come one day yes one day no and for me
I'm a team player I want everybody to be
on the same page together having to
constantly follow up with them and
having to constantly remind them hey
let's get on a zoom let's do this it was
just a drag so if I already had to start
from scratch do it alone don't bring
anybody with you once you're at the top
then you can help them but you have to
get that Foundation created by yourself
the next point is very important because
as soon as I thought I had it figured
out when I learned these platforms and I
learned somewhat of a strategy I tried
to make as much money as possible as
quick as possible as if the market was
going to leave tomorrow I got fomo so
bad that I blew my money faster than I
thought I can ever lose it the Market's
not going anywhere the Market's been
around for tens of years and it's going
to be around for hundreds of years the
opportunities of the market are only
going to get better because more more
data is going to be presented in the
charts so you can use that data to your
advantage to be able to capitalize off
of it so don't think just because you're
getting to start trading right now that
you're late you're not late at all you
might be late to trading but you're not
late to learning a strategy and getting
started today so if I were to start from
scratch it's not chase the money
immediately it's learn the passion and
learn the craft once you learn that the
money will come on its own this next
point is something very personal because
it affected me for about a whole year
into my trading and that is not
listening to your family members or your
close friends what you thought they were
close what you have going for yourself
and what you are challenging yourself to
do is probably one of the most out of
pocket things you can tell to this
generation that isn't introduced to
technology it's just the Simplicity of
the truth making money online without a
college degree without having any type
of education other than a YouTube video
and simply kicking a couple butons one
or two hours a day and you'll be able to
become a millionaire it sounds too good
to be true and explaining to that to my
family to my parents to my cousins that
they had gone to school for years to
become a doctor they just indirectly
hated on me because it was almost like I
was disrespecting what they had worked
for and like hey I just woke up today
and I clicked two buttons and I made 50
Grand I made their whole year salary on
one day and I get it it can be very
frustrating for them at the beginning to
understand it or socially approve it but
what I would recommend is don't tell
anybody what you're doing that way their
negativity does not affect you and I'll
tell you right now you can say it
doesn't affect you but deep down inside
somebody not believing you it does so
the best way to overcome that is not let
the negativity get to you whenever they
ask you hey what are you doing are you
still going to school are you still here
yes whatever you whatever like just give
them what they want to hear but you want
on the back end you're working on your
own craft and I'm going to tell you it's
so much better because you eliminate all
the noise and all of the distractions
trust me if I would have done this at
the beginning I probably would have not
had the emotional barrier that I have
now with my family or my cousins so just
like the previous Point go into this
dark tunnel by yourself and don't ever
look up you look up once the light hits
your face trust me there's light at the
end of the tunnel that leads me to my
next point which is keeping it simple
trading is not complicated people are
going to make it complicated because
they don't know what the [__] they're
talking about people that don't know
what they're talking about should not be
talking about trading and it be the
people out there that don't know about
something that talk about it the most so
don't get distracted with all of the
noise that's out there simply focus on
what works that you have done your
research on and that works and stick to
it the less you do the better and I know
that sounds crazy but trust me it works
this is something that I've learned over
time where I'm in front of the markets
for 1 hour a day and maybe 3 to four
days out of the week and that's it if
I'm in front of the markets more than
three times a week there's something
going on so less is better and if I
would have learned this at year one and
a half of my journey I would have gotten
funded a lot faster and I would have not
failed as many challenges and that is
revolve trading in your results around
percentage do not revolve it around
money let me explain a lot of you guys
want to take a 100 bucks and and flip it
to 500 do you realize that that is 4X
like you're literally multiplying your
money times 4 now let's say if I were to
give you $100,000 and you apply that
same approach you just turn $100,000 to
$500,000 now I say that to you guys and
like oh no that's actually a lot harder
that is more difficult and it's like no
nothing changes it's the same percentage
it's the same exact trade you just risk
the obviously a higher amount on a
bigger account the reality of the
situation is that that money approach is
not realistic you're you're looking at
trading with a little bit of money on
high percentage like it's not a big deal
and then you're looking at low
percentage on high of money like it's
not a big deal as well the goal is make
anywhere from 1 to 2% a week and that is
it if you make to 1 to 2% a week you
will pass any Funding Company challenge
where you can get funded six figure plus
and let's say you take that same
approach to a monthly basis let's say
you average 2% a week that's 8% a month
8% a month on 100K account you're making
$88,000 every single month you're
officially a sixf figure Trader by
simply making 8% a month and it might
sound like a little bit but now take
that same approach to a million doll
account now you're making
$8,000 a month off of 8% now don't get
scared because you see $80,000 or a
million dollar it doesn't matter it's
the same percentage the percentage
applies on any single type of account
across the market do not look at it as
money look at it as percentage and as
soon as that clicked For Me 3 months
later I got my first payout for
$28,000 that is literally what I applied
on the 100 to the mill challenge I had a
percentage goal for every week or every
other week obviously it was an insanely
high percentage but I had a goal of
percentage it wasn't a dollar amount and
that's what led me to turn $100 to 300K
in 3 months and for those of you that
are ready to comment that it's cap it's
it's a fact there's there's 13 or 14
YouTube videos in this channel
documenting the whole entire journey of
me taking every single trade predicting
the before the during the after it's a
whole YouTube series go check it out and
that leads me to my next point because
when I blew the 300K in the challenge I
had forgotten this point right here and
that is losing streaks or losses they're
inevitable I know that they are going to
happen no matter what you can be the
best Trader in the world and you're
going to run into a losing trade a Los
losing week a losing month or maybe even
a losing year and there's absolutely
nothing that you can do about it nothing
you simply just keep it going you don't
know when it's going to stop and you
don't know when it's going to start and
that's the reality of trading and that's
the risk that you take of entering this
game but I can guarantee you that over
the course of 10 to 20 trades with a
positive strategy and the positive
restore War you come out profitable I
didn't accept that a losing streak was a
thing I I didn't accept that a losing
streak could come after five to six
winning traits so if I were to start
from scratch it'd be fully aware that
losses are part of the game and that
losses are only going to make you
sharper and only make you better and as
soon as you Embrace that losses will no
longer get in your way and you simply
treat them like a little poth hole in
the street they're going to happen it
hurts but you just keep it going it's
not going to affect the destination
where you're going to get to that leads
me to my next point which is overtrading
obviously if you take a lot of wins you
want to keep trading so you make more
money and if you take a lot of losses
you want to take more trades so you make
bu the losses and make more money blah
blah blah that is all [__]
overtrading is an equation for failure
at the end of the day the more you trade
the more you lose it's the reality
situation but the more you trade the
more money you will make obviously it
just makes sense now it's how do you
balance that lever how do you know when
to trade more and how do you know when
to trade less so you will avoid the
losing streaks and you capitalize off of
the winning ones that is simply by
trading with the trend but this goes
down to a key level of over trading you
need to set yourself a max amount of
Trades you take in a day in a week in a
month so on and so forth and I
personally do not take more than two
trades a day max risking 1 to 2% of the
account if you do more than that you're
simply over risking your account you're
overexposing it you're risking more than
10% of your account within one single
week if you were to take two trades a
day risking 1% so to eliminate
overtrading as a whole simply just have
anywhere from one to two trades a day
risking 1 to 2% and this way the odds of
you blowing your account are a lot less
and this point right here might actually
be pretty funny which is day trading
doesn't mean everyday trading kind of
crazy right when you're a day trader you
think you come to the market every day
and you're going to trade every day no
because the market is not going to give
you an opportunity every single day and
that took about $30,000 in losses at the
beginning of my journey to realize that
and to realize that that everyday
trading is there the Market's open every
day for you to take a trade but it
doesn't mean that it's ready to align
with your strategy it doesn't mean that
it's ready to risk one or 2% of your
account the quicker you understand that
day trading is not trading every single
day the quicker you will stop losing as
much as you're losing right now and then
swing trading is obviously not trading
from a swing unless if you're trading
with me using my set and forget strategy
along with my students and if you get on
the calls cuz I get on a call with my
students every single week and I break
down the top three top four pairs that
I'm trading for the week I literally
give you the signal I basically give you
the area of Interest where I'm entering
the trade my take profit my stop loss
and this is something that has made
students been able to generate anywhere
from ,000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner Center for
GU strategy now don't get intimidated
the center F strategy is literally for
everybody we have students all around
the world and to make students make an
from $1,000 to $1,500 a week if you want
to know more about what the set and F
strategy is what it consists about and
honestly how it works and how it can
change your life and how it's done it
for not only me but for thousands of
other students click the link in the
description below it's going to be a
very simple video that explains what s
forget strategy is to see if it even
aligns with you because I've had some
traders that have gone from 9 to 5 to
now full-time day Traders and I also
have other people that still work at
their jobs and they use the center
forget strategy to make a side income
with the C strategy so if you guys want
to know more about it click the link in
the description below and I hope you
guys found this video useful and I'll
see you guys in the next one